[Music] Here we go.
让我从一个概念开始给你讲。杰弗里和我将通过这个来工作。
Let me start you out with a concept. And Jeffrey and I are going to work through this.
我们将讨论管道是如何工作的，以及事情是如何进行的。
We're going to talk about how the pipeline works and how things...
当对象被传递时，接收的commandlet如何知道对它们做什么，如果有的话。
when objects get passed, how does the receiving commandlet know what to do with them, if anything at all.
我不是一个善于体育类比的人，因为我对体育一无所知，但据我所知，有一件事是关于小白球的，他们有捕手的手套。
I'm not a good guy with sports analogies because I don't know anything about sports, but as I understand it, there's this thing with the small white balls where they have catcher's mitts.
所以，你知道，发送指令小程序要发送一些棒球，我们要看他们被接收指令小程序抓住了什么捕手的手套。
So, you know, the sending commandlet is going to send some baseballs and we have to see what catcher's mitts they get caught on the receiving commandlet.
你会明白我的意思。
You'll see what I mean.
我们有一个按价值和按属性名称的过程。如果这些都不起作用，我们还有最后一招。
We have a process of by value and by property name. And if those don't work, we have a last line of resort.
所以我只是要，首先，指出所有这些都在幻灯片中，但我不打算使用幻灯片。
So I'm just going to, first of all, point out that all of this is in the slides, but I'm not going to use the slides.
所以我们开始吧。让我们把边上的东西去掉。
So here we go. Let's get rid of the sides.
让我们从一个想法开始。
Let's start with an idea.
获得服务，如果我能拼出它，停止服务。好的。
Get service, if I can spell it, stop service. Okay.
伙计们，我们之前给你们看了这个，我们做了冲刺，如果。你知道这将会起作用。
Guys, we showed you this earlier, and we did dash what if. You know that it's going to work.
但我脑子里的问题是为什么。
But the question that I have in my head is why.
好吧，现在的情况是这样的。获取服务已经...
Well, here's what's happening. Get service has...
得到一堆服务，一堆对象，我们将在管道上一次发送一个对象。
is getting a bunch of services, a bunch of objects, and we're going to send one object at a time across the pipeline.
我的问题是，接收命令的小程序，也就是本例中的停止服务，它是如何抓住这个对象的，又是如何知道该如何处理它的？结果发现，这与接收指令小程序的参数有很大关系。
My question is is the receiving commandlet, which in this case is stop service, how is it grabbing hold of this object and how does it know what to do with it? And as it turns out, it has lot to do with the parameters on the receiving commandlet.
而这正是我想向你展示的。
And that's what I want to show you.
首先，当我们看这个问题时，我们需要知道的第一件事是当我们发...
First of all, one of the first things we need to know when we're looking at this is when we send...
我们要发送对象，我们需要知道它们是什么类型的对象。
we're sending objects, we need to know what kind of objects they are.
所以我用管道把它弄成了会员。
So I piped it to get member.
因为get成员向我展示了在管道中被发送的对象的类型。这是一个服务控制器对象。
Because get member shows me what type of object is being sent across the pipeline. This is a service controller object.
我现在就需要知道这一点。
I need to know that right now.
现在我想做的是，我想看看接收指令小程序能够接收什么。
Now what I want to do is I want to see what the receiving commandlet is capable of receiving.
要做到这一点，我们看一下它的帮助文件，即接收命令小程序。
To do that we look at the help file for it, the receiving commandlet.
在这个过程中，你有一种倾向，就是把管道获取成员和获取帮助混为一谈，但它是通过管道获取成员来查看对象，它是什么类型的，然后我们在接收命令小程序上查看帮助文件。所以让我给你看看。
In this process you have a tendency to get confused between piping to get member and get help, but it's pipe to get member to see the object, what kind it is, and then we look at the help file on the receiving commandlet. So let me show you.
获得关于停止服务的帮助。
Get help on stop service.
现在，我将使用破折号，因为我想让你看到所有的东西，但杰弗里将在这里向你展示一个技巧。
Now, I'm going to use dash full because I want you to see everything, but Jeffrey will show you a trick here in a second.
让我进去给你看看。
Let me go in here and show you.
在里面我们现在非常关注这些信息。我们已经知道如何查看语法了。
Inside we now are very concerned with this information. We already know how to look at the syntax.
我想在这里下去看一下参数。
I want to go down here and look at the parameters.
参数有时有一个能力，这个能力就是它们是否接受管道输入。
The parameters have a capability sometimes and that capability is do they accept pipeline input.
现在，想想这些人的参数就是有无捕手手套的事情。
Now, think of these guys as the parameters are the things with or without the catcher's mitt.
因此，我们要问的是，你是否有一个捕手的手套，在那里你可以抓住这个物体并对它做一些事情。
So what we're asking is do you have a catcher's mitt or not where you could catch this object and do something with it.
嗯，很多时候你会看到像显示名称，它不接受管道输入。
Well, a lot of times you'll see like display name, it doesn't accept pipeline input.
所以没有什么要跨越的。但让我们沿着这个名单往下看。
So there's nothing going to cross. But let's go down this list.
我经常从底部开始，但让我们沿着这个名单往下看。
I often start at the bottom, but let's go down this list.
而这是停止服务。所以让我们在这里看看。冲刺如果。
And this is stop service. So let's see here. Dash what if.
好吧，破折号如果，它甚至对接受管道输入没有意义。破折号确认。不，这并不接受它。
Well, dash what if, it doesn't even make sense to the accept pipeline input. Dash confirm. No, that doesn't accept it.
PassThru，这不接受。Dash名称。它接受它。
PassThru, that doesn't accept it. Dash name. That does accept it.
现在，我们关心的是这个问题。
Now here's what we're concerned about.
我们有两种接受管道输入的方式，分别是通过值和通过属性名称。
We have two ways of accepting pipeline input by value and by property name.
如果你是一个开发人员，我们不是在谈论按元音，按参考文献，这是不一样的。而是按价值和按属性名称。
And if you're a dev out there, we're not talking about by vowel, by ref, this is different. But by value and by property name.
我们要尝试的第一种方式是通过价值。
The first way we're going to try it is by value.
而你在这里要注意的是，冲锋枪的名字支持按值接受管道输入。
And what you're going to notice here is dash name supports accepting pipeline input by value.
而且你会喜欢某种字符串。
And you would like some kind of string.
好吧，等一下，让我给你看看这个，让我再往上走一点。
Well, wait a second, let me show this to you, let me go up a little bit further.
看到这个叫做输入对象的参数了吗？我不太清楚它的作用，但它的值是接受真。
See this parameter called input object? I'm not exactly sure what it does, but it accepts true by value.
看看它喜欢什么样的对象，一个服务控制器。
Look at the kind of object it would like, a service controller.
等一下，等一下，等一下。
Wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute.
当我得到服务时，我向它发送的是什么样的对象？我发送的是一个服务控制器。
When I did get service, what kind of object was I sending it? I was sending a service controller.
因此，当一个服务控制器穿越管道来停止服务时，要抓住它的捕捉器是输入参数捕捉器，因为这个名字的拼写与我发送的对象类型的服务控制器完全一样。
So when a service controller comes cruising across that pipeline to stop service, the catcher's mitt that's going to grab it is the input parameter catcher's mitt because this name is spelled exactly like service controller of the object type that I sent.
我知道这很奇怪，但它们的拼写是一样的。
I know this is weird, but they're spelled the same.
因此，由于它们的拼写相同，这意味着我们实际上是按值传递。
So since they're spelled the same, this means we're actually passing it by value.
而这是最有效的传递方式之一。因此，这就是获取服务和停止服务的实际工作方式。
And this is one of the most efficient ways to pass. So that's how get service and stop service actually work.
我们通过价值传递到参数输入对象中，因为名称匹配，对象的类型与参数的期望值一致。
We're passing by value into the parameter input object because the names match, the type of object along with what the parameter expects.
这里就变得有点棘手了。
Here's where it gets a little tricky.
如果你想对我大喊大叫，请马上跳进来。
And please jump in as soon as you want to yell at me about something.
你做得很好。
You're doing great.
你这么认为吗？因为，伙计，这对我来说一开始很困难。
You think so? Because, man, this was hard on me at first.
但我一拿到这个，这就...
But as soon as I got this, this is...
You got it....
是什么让世界变得震撼。
what made the world rock.
我们来试试这个。请注意，我确实得到了服务停止服务。
Let's try this. Notice that I did get service stop service.
我想向你指出一点。注意这些名词是如何匹配的。
And I want to point something out to you. Notice how the nouns match.
那么，如果名词匹配，他们很可能会在一条管道上合作。
Well, if the nouns match, it's likely that they're going to work together on a pipeline.
也有可能他们可能会通过价值。但这并不总是这样的。
It's also likely that they'll probably pass by value. But it's not always the case.
所以你总是想检查以确保。
So you always want to check to make sure.
让我给你看一些名词不匹配的地方。
Let me show you something where the nouns don't match.
获得服务停止程序。嗯，这是两件完全不同的事情。
Get service stop process. Well, these are two totally different things.
服务，流程。它们不是一回事。
Services, processes. They're not the same thing.
所以我敢打赌，你们大多数人都在想和我一样的事情。
So I'll bet most of you are thinking the same thing that I am.
这是不可能的。
This isn't going to work.
它不可能发挥作用。服务，流程。
It can't possibly work. Services, processes.
让我们通过这个过程，看一看。
Let's go through this process and take a look.
我将做得到的服务，我将管它得到的成员。
I'm going to do get service and I'm going to pipe it to get member.
我知道我们知道这个问题的答案，但我只想再走一遍这个过程。
I know we know the answer to this, but I just want to go through the process again.
我们正在发送什么样的对象，我们正在发送一个服务控制器对象。
What kind of object are we sending, we're sending a service controller object across.
现在，我想检查的第一件事是看在停止过程中是否有东西支持这个对象的管道输入值。
Now, the first thing I want to check is to see if there's something in stop process that supports pipeline input by value for this object.
这将是我们挂钩的第一种方式。
That would be the first way we would hook up.
因此，我将在接收命令小程序上获得帮助，在这种情况下，它是停止进程，让我们快速看一下。
So I'm going to do get help on the receiving commandlet, which in this case is stop process, and let's take a quick look.
让我上去看一下参数。
Let me get up to the parameters.
现在，伙计们，我要把这个缩短一点，因为我知道有些参数就是不接受管道输入的，比如它不接受管道输入怎么办。所以我甚至不需要看它。
Now, guys, I'm going to shorten this down a little bit because I know some of these parameters just don't accept pipeline input, like what if it doesn't accept pipeline input. So I don't even need to look at it.
因此，每次它说假的时候，我都对它不太感兴趣。
So every time it says false, I'm not really interested in it.
PassThru，不支持，dash name，它确实支持，但现在我是按值检查的。这是按属性名称。
PassThru, doesn't support it, dash name, it does support it but right now I'm checking for by value. This is by property name.
所以我在按价值寻找东西。
So I'm looking for things by value.
啊，我们走吧。输入对象。它支持管道输入。
Ah, there we go. Input object. It supports pipeline input.
它将抓住它。
It will catch it.
而它是通过我们要做的第一种方式的价值来做的，但看看它想要什么，一个进程对象。
And it's doing it by value the first way we're going to do it, but look at what it wants, a process object.
好吧，我不送了。
Well, I'm not sending it.
流程与服务控制器的拼写方式不一样。
Process isn't spelled the same way as service controller.
还差得远呢。
Not even close.
所以这里不会有勾搭，所以按价值来说是失败的。
So there's not going to be a hookup here, so by value fails.
好吧，现在在这一点上，你有点去，好吧，如果它失败了，它只是不会工作。
Well, now at this point you kind of go, well, if it fails, it's just not going to work.
不，现在我们进入下一个过程，即按财产名称。
No. Now we move on to the next process which is by property name.
而这就有点令人困惑了。
And this gets a little bit confusing.
我想让你注意到，当我在这个帮助文件中。
I want you to notice while I'm in this help file.
看到参数dash name是如何通过属性名称进行管道输入的吗？这是在说什么。
See how the parameter dash name takes pipeline input by property name? Here's what that's saying.
你发送给我的对象，它是否有一个与参数名称拼写完全相同的属性。
The object that you're sending to me, does it have a property that is spelled exactly like the parameter name.
这就是我们所说的财产名称，它的拼写是否相同。如果是这样的话，我也许可以用这种方式来连接。
That's what we mean by property name, is it's spelled the same. And if so, I might be able to hook up that way.
如果我的声母失败了，我就试试这个。所以我打算这样做。
If my vowel fails, I'll try this. So here's what I'm going to do.
这里有一句套话。
Here's the catch phrase.
每当你想知道关于一个对象的所有信息时，你就用管道来获取成员。
Whenever you want to know everything there is to know about an object, you pipe it to get member.
所以要得到服务。
So get service.
而我要把它管起来，以获得成员。
And I'm going to pipe it to get member.
看看这个名单。
Take a look at this list.
是否有财产... 记住我们不...
Is there a property... and remember we don't...
我们需要的是财产这个词......
alls we need is the word property...
是否有一个属性与参数名称的拼写方式相同。
is there a property that is spelled the same way as the parameter name.
如果你看一下这个名单，啦啦，有。
And if you look at the list, la-la, there is.
如果它们的拼写相同，我们就要按财产名称进行挂钩。
If they're spelled the same, we're going to have a hookup by property name.
如果你看一下这个名单，啦啦，有。
And if you look at the list, la-la, there is.
如果它们的拼写相同，我们就会有一个按属性名称的钩子。但注意这里会发生什么。
If they're spelled the same, we're going to have a hookup by property name. But watch what's going to happen here.
所以我们来看看。我在这里只接受一项服务。
So let's look. I'm only going to take one service here.
服务。看看它的名字是什么。它是服务的名称。
Service. Look at what its name is. It's the name of the service.
好的。等一下。
Okay. Wait a second.
当你看进程的时候，让我们看看进程，进程的名字也是名字。
When you look at processes, let's look at processes, process name is also name.
这些是进程名称。因此，当你使用commandlet...
These are process names. So when you use the commandlet...
哎呀。清除屏幕。当你使用commandlet的时候...
oops. Clear the screen. When you use the commandlet...
你好，清除屏幕。我们走吧。
hello, clear the screen. There we go.
当你使用commandlet stop process时，它所希望的破折号是一个进程的名称。
When you use the commandlet stop process, what it wants for its dash name is the name of a process.
我发给它的是一个服务的名称。
What I'm sending it is the name of a service.
但事情是这样的。
But here's the thing.
我们确实有一个钩子。
We do have a hookup.
这是要工作的，只是你的结果可能有点不寻常。所以我们来试试吧。获取服务。
This is going to work, it's just your results may be a little unusual. So let's try it. Get service.
管子来停止进程。这应该是有效的。
Pipe to stop process. This should work.
而且，是的，我要做一个冲刺的如果，因为......。
And, yeah, I'm going to do a dash what if because...
你知道我为什么要做一个冲刺的假设吗？因为它确实是有效的。
you know why I'm doing a dash what if? Because it does actually work.
注意到我的屏幕上有很多血迹。
Notice there's a lot of blood on my screen.
现在，这意味着，是的，看，找不到有这个名字的进程。
Now, what this means is is that, yeah, look, cannot find the process with the name.
嗯，是的，因为那是一个服务名称。
Well, yeah, because that's a service name.
当然你找不到。
Of course you can't find that.
但是如果你看这里，你有没有看到有白色的东西飞过？因为那意味着它起作用了。让我看看我是否能找到什么。
But if you look here, did you see anything white fly by? Because that means it worked. Let me see if I can find something.
哦，总是有的。
Oh, there's always something.
我什么也没看到。
I didn't see anything.
真的吗？不是。
Really? No.
不要在我的朋友面前让我难堪。
Don't embarrass me in front of my friends.
只有5,000或2。
It's only 5,000 or 2.
我知道。有...
I know. There's...
这里面几乎总有一些东西是白色的。
there's almost always something in here that's in white.
到我这里来。让我给你看看。
Go to mine. Let me show you.
去找他。
Go to his.
好吧，那么这里是...我将做一个不同的设置。
Okay. So here's... I'll do a different set.
好的。很好。
Okay. Cool.
好吗？所以注意我在这里开始了计算器。
Okay? So notice I started up calculator here.
因此，我可以做得到的过程。
And so I can do get process.
计算并得到计算器。我可以用管道把它送到dir。
Calc and get calculator. And I can pipe that to dir.
我们看到，计算在这里面。为什么是这样呢？因为dir需要...
And we see that calc is in this. And why is that? Because dir takes...
绑定的名字，于是你看了一眼。
binds by name, and so you take a look.
那么，Dir是否需要一个进程，你知道，system.diagnostics.process？没有。
And, well, does dir take a process, you know, system.diagnostics.process? No.
它说，哦，好吧，我用名字来绑定任何东西。
And it says, oh, well, I bind anything by name.
你有一个名字吗？而得到的过程确实有一个名字，因此它是有效的。
Do you have a name? And get process does have a name, and therefore it works.
而这是一个很好的例子。
And that's an excellent example.
所以在他的例子和我的例子之间，你得到了这里发生的事情，就是小命令在一起工作，但你必须看看你给它的东西，你给的信息和它期望的东西。
And so between his example and mine, you get what's happening here, is that the commandlets are working together, but you have to look at what you're giving it, the information that you're giving and what it's expecting.
在我的获取服务停止进程的情况下，如果你有一个正在运行的进程恰好与一个服务的名称相同，它就会被杀死。
In the case of my get service stop process, if you have a process running that happens to have the same name as a service, it's going to get killed off.
大多数时候，情况并非如此。
Most of the time that's not the case.
在Jeffrey的例子中，我得到了一个进程名称，而这个名称恰好是我可以去寻找的一个文件。因此，这是一个很好的结果，可以解决。
In Jeffrey's example, I got a process name that happens to be actually a file I could go looking for. So that is a good result that works out.
我可以给他们看......实际上，你知道吗，我说错了。
Can I show them... actually, you know what, I said that wrong.
这实际上是一个路径...
It was actually the path...
把它的路径......
The path that put it......
是导演。是的。
is the dir. Yeah.
所以dir需要一个路径，而进程对象有一个路径。现在，注意到在我的屏幕上，我们说，哦，你知道，按名字。
So dir takes a path, and process object has a path. Now, notice in my screen we said, oh, you know, by name.
那么，你是指名道姓地做的，对吗？对。
Well, you were doing it by name, right? Right.
GSWB。并注意到这里有一个名字。
GSWB. And notice here's a name.
我想给你看的是什么？通过...
What was it I wanted to show you? Through...
好的。所以注意到这里的事情。
okay. So notice this thing here.
是的。
Yeah.
好的。名称，别名属性服务名称。所以不像...
Okay. Name, alias property service name. So unlike...
记得，我说过，PowerShell，我们专注于让你的生活变得美好，因为那些人并不专注于此，对吧，他们专注于我为自己写这个，这将是很酷的，或者，嘿，你是我的开发者伙伴，我们要互相谈论开发者的谈话，等等，等等。
remember, I said that PowerShell, we're focused in on making your life good because those people aren't focused in on that, right, they're focused in on I'm writing this for myself, it's going to be cool, or, hey, you're my developer buddy and we're going to talk developer talk to each other, blah, blah, blah.
因此，这是个相当不一致的世界。
And so it's pretty inconsistent world.
我们有责任努力使它成为一个符合你的世界。
We're responsible for trying to make it a consistent world for you.
因此，虽然你说服务名称和过程是过程名称，但我们想说，不，你不关心所有这些废话，你只想知道名称。
So whereas you say service name and process was process name, we want to say, no, you don't care about all that crap, you just want the name.
名称。
Name.
好吧，好吧，好吧，好吧。
Okay.
因此，我们所做的是我们采取类型系统，记得我是如何向你展示XML的，我们调整了XML，并把它更简单地呈现给你。
And so what we do is we take the type system, and remember how I showed you XML, we tweaked the XML and we present it to you simpler.
我们为此所做的技术之一是一个叫做别名属性的东西。
One of the techniques we do for that is something called an alias property.
一个别名属性就是在这里，我们说，嘿，我们有这个属性名称，它被别名为服务名称。
An alias property is something here, we say, hey, we have this property name which is aliased to service name.
因此，财产...
So the property...
对象本身实际上只有一个叫做服务名称的东西，但我们说，嘿，把它当作它有一个名字，当你要求它时，给他们服务名称。
the object itself really only has this thing called service name, but we say, hey, treat it as though it has a name which... and when you ask for it, give them the service name.
这使得它...
And that makes it...
这给了你一个简化的一致的世界观，它使这个互操作性的东西发挥作用。
that gives you a simplified consistent view of the world, and it makes this interoperability stuff work.
因为如果结果是，嘿，我想发送一些东西到一些命令，而它接受的东西是由咕咕罐[音译]和......
Because if it turns out that, hey, I want to send something to some command and it's accepting things by goo jar [Phonetic] and...
Right....
而我也有一个，但我称它为foo[音译]。
and I have one of those, but I call it a foo [Phonetic].
对。
Right.
我只是去说，好吧，在我的foo上，你知道，我要把它的名字映射到goo jar上，我做一次，然后我可以把它发送给你。
I just go and I say, okay, well, on my foo, you know, I'm going to map its name to goo jar, I do that once, and then I can send it to you.
事实上，这是一个完美的设置，在此第一阶段。因此，理解他的...
As a matter of fact, this is a perfect setup for the first stage in this. And so understand what he's...
他向你展示的是，他们已经做了大量的工作来使PowerShell命令保持一致。
he's shown you is that they've done a lot of work to make PowerShell commands consistent.
换句话说，我们在对象上有一个服务名称，但他们创建了一个名为name的别名属性，所以它可以与其他接受属性名称的小命令一起工作。
In other words, we had a service name on the object, but they created an alias property called name so it could work with other commandlets that accept by property name.
所以他们他们为我们做的是一致的。
So they they're making it consistent for us.
但有些时候，最伟大的思想都有相同的想法，只是还没有机会让一切都保持一致。
But there are times when the greatest minds all think alike but just haven't had a chance to get everything consistent yet.
让我给你举个例子，这将会在哪里发生故障。
Let me give you an example where this is going to break down.
这是我最喜欢的一个小命令，就是获取AD电脑。
This is one of my favorite commandlets, is get AD computer.
我需要告诉你，你需要有点小心的是，微软，特别是产品团队在处理这个问题时，他们试图帮助你，不要对自己做危险的事情。
And I need to tell you that one of the things you need to be kind of careful with is Microsoft, especially the product teams when they work with this, they try to help you by not doing dangerous things to yourself.
想一想这个小命令所要做的事情下面的技术。
Think about the technology underneath what this commandlet's going to do.
如果我运行这个，谁拥有这些信息？域控制器有。
If I run this, who has this information? Domain controller does.
因此，这个小命令必须去找域控制器，向域控制器询问这些信息，然后把这些信息吐出来。
So this commandlet has to go out to a domain controller, ask the domain controller for this information and then spit this information back.
听着，很诚实地讲，如果你只有几十台电脑，这不是什么大问题。
Look, quite honestly, if you only have a couple dozen computers, that's not a big deal.
但如果你有30,000台电脑，这可能是一个大问题。
But if you have 30,000 computers, this could be a big deal.
这可能使你的域控制器在一段时间内不是域控制器。
This could make your domain controller not a domain controller for a while.
然后当它把数据吐出来时，你可能会有一段时间的性能问题。
And then when it spits the data back, you could have some performance issues for a while.
因此，当你运行commandlet时，你会注意到，你知道，很多时候你会做一个get commandlet，它就会运行。
So when you're running commandlets, you will notice, you know, a lot of times you'll do a get commandlet and it will just run.
指挥部可能会有一点危险，情况并非如此。他们所做的是把一些强制性的东西放在其中。
Commandlets that might be a little bit more dangerous, that's not the case. What they do is they put things in them that are mandatory.
我们在前面提到了获取事件日志的问题。
We mentioned this with get event log earlier.
这是另一个伟大的小命令，有一个例子。所以让我给你看看。
This is another great commandlet that has an example. So let me show you.
如果我只是在获取AD电脑上敲击回车键，呵呵--呃，兄弟，你得给我一点关于这个的更多信息。
If I just strike enter on get AD computer, huh-uh, bro, you got to give me a little bit more information about this.
你一定要...我不想把所有东西都给你。
You've got to be... I don't want to get you everything.
真的吗？所以我就放了一颗星。
Really? So I'm just going to put in a star.
这将起作用，它将使我得到一切。
This will work and it will get me everything.
但请注意我做了什么。
But notice what I've done.
现在是我做了决定，要真正得到一切。
I'm the one now that's made the decision to actually get everything.
所以这是我要用的小命令。所以，让我这样做。获取AD计算机。
So this is the commandlet that I'm going to use for a second. So let me do this. Get AD computer.
而我只是要把过滤器，星星，这意味着我要抓住一切。
And I'm just going to put in the filter, star, which means I'm going to grab everything.
而我想......这是我的商业问题。
And I want to... here's my business problem.
我想做的是获得网络中每台计算机上的比特服务的状态。
What I would like to do is get the status of the bit service on every computer in the network.
我知道这听起来没那么有创意，但以后会越来越好。因此，获得服务名称位。
I know it doesn't sound that creative, but it gets better later. So get service name bits.
明白我想做什么。
Understand what I'm trying to do.
我试图从活动目录中获得一个所有计算机的列表，我想让它们通过管道进入获取服务，这样，获取服务就会从所有的计算机中获取位服务。好吧，事情是这样的。
I'm trying to get a list of all the computers from active directory, and I want them piped to get service and so that get service will then grab the bit service from all of them. Well, here's the thing.
让我们看看我们是否能弄清楚这将如何工作或不工作。
Let's see if we can figure out how this is going to work or not work.
因此，我们所做的第一件事是，我经历了整个过程，首先，向总经理汇报，以了解我正在处理的是什么样的对象。
So first thing is that we do is I go through the whole process, first of all, pipe to GMs to find out what kind of object am I working with.
我需要知道这一点，以备它对按价值计算的工作。因此，AD计算机对象。听起来不错。
I need to know this for by value in case it works for by value. So AD computer object. Sounds great.
可能不会发生，因为名词不匹配，但AD计算机对象，太好了。
Probably ain't gonna happen because the nouns don't match, but AD computer object, great.
我接下来要做的事情是在获得服务上得到帮助，看看是否......dadadadada......。
Next thing I'm going to do is get help on get service and see if it... dadadadada...
如果支持AD计算机对象的值，可以看到它。
see it if supports AD computer object by value.
而且，伙计们，我将使这一点更简短。因此，与其滚动浏览每个...
And, guys, I'm going to make this a little bit briefer. So rather than scrolling through every...
并在每一个人身上停下来，让我滚动到按价值计算的东西上。
and stopping at every single one of them, let me just scroll up to the things that say by value.
我可以向他们展示一招吗？是的，当然可以。
Can I show them a trick? Yeah, sure.
再做一次，做减法显示窗口。
Do that again and do minus show window.
所以做展示窗口，好的。
So do show window, okay.
是的，展示窗口。好的。因此，如果你有...
Yeah, show window. Okay. And so if you have...
现在，按数值搜索。
now search by by value.
哦。伙计，看，这整个... 这整个节目...
Oh. Man, see, this whole... this whole show...
这整个展示橱窗的事情实在是太棒了。
this whole show window thing is just awesome.
是的。然后打下一个。
Yeah. And then hit next.
哦，等一下。我必须要打下一个。我们走吧。
Oh, wait a minute. I have to hit next. There we go.
哦，孩子，一个物体。
Oh, boy, an object.
那是一个物体。
That's an object.
这很容易还是什么看到了吗？看到了吗？所以现在看，看，看，我们得到了它。接受管道输入。
Was that easy or what see? See? So now look, look, look, we got it. Accept pipeline input.
你可能要看我的卷轴，真的，通过价值，我们看起来不错。
You may have to watch me scroll, true, by value, we're looking good.
输入对象想要什么样的对象？它想要一个...
What kind of object does input object want? It wants a...
这与AD电脑的拼写方式完全一样吗？不是。
is that spelled exactly the same way as AD computer? No.
因此，按价值来说，没有勾兑。
So no hookup by value.
如此接近。
So close.
是的，如此接近。
Yeah, so close.
[笑声]所以我们要做的，是通过属性名称来检查。
[Laughter] So what we're going to do, then, is check for by property name.
好吧，我得看看有什么属性。
Well, I have to take a look at what the properties are.
而实际上，我所关心的唯一的属性是我试图发送的是持有计算机名称的东西。
And really the only property I care about that I'm trying to send across is whatever holds the computer name.
因此，让我们真正快速地看一下。
So let's take a look at that real quick.
拿到AD电脑，过滤星，嗯，哎呀，奇了怪了，就拿其中一个。
Get AD computer, filter star, well, gee, whiz, just take one of them.
有一大堆的东西被送过管道。
There's a whole bunch of stuff that's being sent across the pipe.
不过，我唯一关心的是计算机名称的位置。而这个属性被称为名字。
The only thing I care about, though, is where the computer name is. And that property is called name.
因此，让我们回到展示窗口，看看我们是否有支持名称的东西。
So let's go back to the show window and see if we have something that supports name.
所以管道，按属性名称，所以让我们做这个技巧，按属性名称，看看会发生什么。
So pipeline, by property name, and so let's do this trick, by property name, and watch what happens.
所以我们会找到他们。
So we'll find them.
小飞的计算机名称。嘿，这支持按属性名称。
Dash computer name. Hey, that supports by property name.
但要记住规则是什么。
But remember what the rule is.
这必须是完全这样拼写的，才能由财产来挂钩。而事实并非如此。
This has to be spelled exactly like this for by property to hook up. And it's not.
事实上，它的拼写也不一样。
In fact, it's not spelled the same.
但你知道如果我在这里下去的话，什么东西的拼写是一样的？哎呀。等等。哪条路？看吧。
But you know what is spelled the same if I go down here? Oops. Wait. Which way? Looky.
目的。
Aim.
我们确实支持按财产名称对拼写完全相同的东西。但看看它说什么。它想要一个服务名称。
We do support by property name on something spelled exactly the same. But look at what it says. It wants a service name.
因此，将发生的事情是这样的。
So here's what's going to happen.
如果我试着运行这个，我就会取一堆计算机名称，它就会认为我在给它提供服务名称。
If I try to run this, I'm going to take a bunch of computer names and it's going to think that I'm giving it service names.
除非你以服务命名你的计算机，这绝不是一个好主意，否则这是不可能的。问题是...
And unless you named your computers after services, which would never be a good idea, this is not going to work. The thing is...
真正让我感动的是，上帝，如果有一种方法，如果有一种方法，我不希望这被称为名字，我希望它被称为计算机名称，因为如果它被称为计算机名称，那么它将与我们的所有工作相匹配......
that really gets me is, God, if there was only a way, if there only was a way where I don't want this to be called name, I want it to be called computer name, because if it's called computer name then it would match in everything we're work...
如果能有办法让我把这个属性改成计算机名称的话。
if there was only a way I could change this property to say computer name.
然而却有。
And yet there is.
你想给他们看吗？你想给他们看吗？我没有AD电脑。
Do you want to show them? You want to show them? I don't have AD computer.
哦。那是......你没有AD电脑。
Oh. That's... you don't have AD computer.
好吧，那就让我给他们看看。
Well, let me show them then.
所以我们来做这个概念。所以看着吧，伙计们。
So let's do the concept. So watch, guys.
看一看。
Take a look.
获得服务。而我只是要向你展示一个快速的概念。
Get service. And I'm just going to show you a quick concept.
我想让你们看到，我只是要与一项服务合作，以保持简单。你们之前已经看到了一个精选的属性...
I want you to see, I'm just going to work with one service to keep it simple. You guys have seen a select properties before...
顺便说一句，我认为你没有给他们看电脑名称。
By the way, I don't think you've shown them computer name.
你给他们看了电脑名称吗？所以，你知道，得到的服务是针对[听不清]电脑的。
Have you shown them computer name? So, you know, get service works against [Inaudible] computers.
是的。哦，是的。是的，我应该在帮助文件中告诉你。
Yes. Oh, yeah. Yeah, I should have shown you in the help file.
你会看到它有冲刺的计算机名称。
You'll see it has dash computer name.
因此，我可以用它来对付远程计算机，这也是我想让活动目录命令小程序做的。
So I could use this against remote computers, which is what I'm trying to get the active directory commandlet to do.
是的。
Yeah.
我要抓住名字和地位，我希望你们能看到一些东西。
I'm going to grab name and status, and I want you guys to see something.
是的，它要在状态中给我的名字。
Yeah, it's going to give me the name in the status.
这是你所期望的。
That's what you would expect.
但是，如果出现这种情况，你们中有多少人会想到会出现错误？而通常当我在会议上时，这正是我所打的字。因为我不能很好地打字。
But how many of you would expect to get an error if this occurred? And usually when I'm at a conference, this is exactly what I type. Because I can't type very well.
因此，它通常会出现纳姆-斯特斯。
So it usually comes naem stitus.
看看会发生什么。
Watch what happens.
看到了吗？你明白这里发生了什么吗？等一下。
See that? Do you get what's going on here? Wait a minute.
很多人认为这应该产生一个错误。这不应该产生一个错误。那是一个功能。
A lot of people think that that should generate an error. That shouldn't generate an error. That's a feature.
让我给你看看。我将用管子来获取成员。
Let me show you. I'm going to pipe that to get member.
看。
Look.
它只是创造了新的属性，称为naem和stitus。
It just created new properties called naem and stitus.
[笑声]所以，想法是这样的。我想让你考虑一下这个问题。
[Laughter] So here's the idea. I want you to think about this.
我想知道我是否可以把AD计算机的现有属性称为名称，并把它改为计算机名称。答案是肯定的。
I wonder if I could take the existing property for AD computer called name and change it to computer name. And the answer is yes.
然而，答案是肯定的，但让我告诉你这将如何运作。
However, the answer is yes, but let me show you how this is going to work.
首先，我将选择属性名称，以便你能看到我没有作弊，然后我将向你展示一些特殊的语法。
First of all, I'm going to select the property name just so you can see I'm not cheating, and then I'm going to show you some special syntax.
而这个语法一开始有点拗口，但它在select dash对象的帮助文件中。
And this syntax at first is a little chewy, but it's in the help file for the select dash object.
而这是在例子中。
And it's in the example.
这将是你要学习的内容之一。
That's going to be one of the things you want to learn.
这是一种哈希表的语法。
It's a hash table syntax.
是的。
Yes.
而且我们到处都在使用哈希表。
And we use hash tables everywhere.
所以你要花时间，你要学习语法。
So you're going to spend the time, you're going to learn the syntax.
这个语法你必须...你必须...
This syntax you must... you must...
你只能不断地输入，直到你学会为止。
you're just going to have keep typing it till you learn it.
这是你要保持的东西。所以它是一个带有开放斜线的at标志。
This is something you're going to have to keep in. So it's an at sign with an open squiggly.
而我们所拥有的是一个叫做名字等值的词，现在你可以创建你自己的财产名称。
And what we have is the word called name equals and now you get to create your own property name.
我希望这个东西被称为什么？我希望它被称为计算机名称。
What would I like this to be called? I want it to be called computer name.
所以我打算把电脑的名字放进去。
So I'm going to put in computer name.
在这一点上，分号，然后你指定表达式，将用数据填充该列。
And at this point, semicolon, and then you specify the expression that will fill that column with data.
好吧，让我们来做这个。表达式等于。
Well, let's do this. Expression equals.
而你要把它放在方块字的里面。
And you're going to put that inside of squigglies.
而且还有一个斜线留下了。
And there's one squiggly left over.
所以在这里里面我们要的是管道上的当前对象美元符号下划线，或者你可以用美元符号PS项目与版本3。
So inside here we want the current object on the pipeline dollar sign underscore or you can use dollar sign PS item with Version 3.
我想从来自AD计算机的对象中得到什么？我想要原始名称属性。所以看。名称。
And what do I want from the object that's coming from get AD computer? I want the original name property. So watch. Name.
我打算罢工进入，并观察会发生什么。
I'm going to strike enter, and watch what happens.
哦哦。
Oohhh.
帅哥，帅哥，帅哥，哦，我现在给自己起了个电脑名，是个财产。
Dudes, dudettes, dudesses, oh, I've got myself a computer name now property.
现在，让我告诉你，你将如何在互联网上看到这个。有几件快速的事情。这是一个...
Now, let me just show you how you're going to see this on the Internet. A couple of just quicky things. This is a...
你会听到这个自定义列、计算属性，人们用所有这些术语来形容它。
you'll hear this custom columns, calculated properties, people use all these terms for this.
但你几乎从未见过有人用这种完整的语法打字。
But you almost never see anybody type in this full syntax.
他们要把这个缩短到只有一个E，然后他们要把这个缩短到只有一个N。
They're going to shorten this up to just an E, then they're going to shorten this up to just an N.
为什么呢？因为它很短。
And why? Because it's short.
因为我是一个有趣的人。
Because I'm a fun person.
我不会打字。
I can't type.
我根本无法打字。
I can't type at all.
我不可能弄清楚如何拼写表达。
There's no way I'm going to figure out how to spell expression.
表达？我知道。我知道。
Expression? I know. I know.
但是，看，伙计们，我想让你们看到这仍然有效。所以我已经改变了它。
But, watch, guys, I want you to see that this still works. So I've changed it.
还有一件事我想告诉你，你会在互联网上经常看到这个，你需要注意。
One other thing I want show you, you're going to see this a lot on the Internet, and you need to watch out for it.
过去，这被称为标签，而不是名字。
Used to be instead of name this was called label.
而每个人都会把这个缩写为L。
And everybody would abbreviate this as an L.
好吧，我不知道你的情况，但是当你在博客文章或书中看到这个时，你无法区分L和数字1之间的区别。
Well, I don't know about you, but when you see this on a blog post or in a book, you can't tell the difference between an L and the number 1.
因此，很多时候你会打错字，然后你会说，这根本行不通。
So a lot of times you'll type it in wrong and you'll go, It just doesn't work.
没有。
No.
如果你看到一个L或看起来像1的东西，一定要用N来代替；这样你就可以摆脱所有这些小的模糊的...
If you ever see an L or what looks to be a 1, always replace it with an N; that way you get rid of all of those little ambigu-...
我不能说这个词，但所有这些小问题，模棱两可......
I can't say that word, but all those little problems, ambig-...
是的，所有这些小问题。
yeah, all those little problems.
需要通配符进行演讲。
Need wild cards for speech.
[笑声]所以我们来做这个。
[Laughter] So let's do this.
我真的不需要这个名字在这里了，因为我已经设法创造了我自己的版本。
I don't really need this name in here anymore because I've managed to create my own version.
我想告诉你，如果你用管道来获取成员，看到它说的是计算机名称。所以，看看吧。
And I want to show you if you pipe it to get member, see it says computer name. So looky.
当我们把它传递给接收的commandlet时，计算机名称要与计算机名称相匹配，通过属性名称，瞧，dununa-dununa-dununa，鼓声，鼓声，鼓声，命令是获得服务名称位。
When we pass it to the receiving commandlet, computer name is going to match with computer name, by property name, and, lo and behold, dununa-dununa-dununa, drum roll, drum roll, drum roll, and the command was get service name bits.
呜呜呜。
Woooo.
哦，来吧，那是如此邪恶的酷。
Oh, come on, that is so wickedly cool.
呜呼。
Whoo.
[笑声]后面的人都在说，我不知道他刚才做了什么，但是，好吧，我们就跟着做吧。
[Laughter] The guys in the back are going I don't know what the hell he just did, but, okay, we'll go with it.
呜呼。
Woohoo.
乞求掌声。
Begging for the applause.
是的，怜悯的掌声。高尔夫掌声。
Yeah, pity applause. Golf clap.
问题是，你知道，他们正在努力尝试，你知道，给你别名属性，以使一些一致性，但这并不总是会发生的。
Here's the thing, is that, you know, they're working to try to, you know, give you alias properties to make some consistencies, but that's not always going to be the case.
有时，你是必须在飞行中使用自定义列或计算属性来做一致性的工作。
Sometimes you're the one that has to do it in-flight to make the consistency using a custom column or calculated property.
我们经常使用这些东西，因为我们可以用它做很多事情。
We use these a ton because there's so much we can do with this.
我们可以用这个做很多事情。
So much we can do with this.
你会看到我们在这里使用它的一些更多的例子。
And you'll see some more examples of us using it in here.
但我们确实有最后...
But we do have the last...
最后一种可能性。
the last possibility.
这是我最喜欢的一个。
It's my favorite one.
因为当我这样做时，每个人都对我大喊大叫。
Because everybody yells at me when I do this.
顺便说一句，在这个东西上花时间真的很值得。
By the way, it's really worth spending time on this stuff.
这就是PowerShell的核心。
This is the heart of PowerShell.
这是核心概念，这是核心力量，这是你获得所有魔法的地方，所以学习这个东西，比如花一些时间，了解它真正的工作原理，熟悉哪里，管道，是它的核心。这就是投资。
This is the core concept, it's the core power, it's where you get all your magic, so learning this stuff, like spending some time, understanding how it really works, getting familiar with the where, the pipelining, is the heart of it. It's the investment.
好吧，我只是不得不说，这绝对是...
Well, and I just have to say, and this is definitely...
对我来说，伙计们，这就是改变我使用PowerShell的能力的原因。
for me, guys, this is what changed my ability to be productive with PowerShell.
当我学会这个的时候，这就是突然让PowerShell，哦，我明白了。
When I learned this, this is what suddenly made PowerShell, oh, I got this.
因为我可以发现我正在寻找的任何东西，现在我知道如何把它放在一起。
Because I could discover whatever it is I was looking for and now I knew how to put it together.
如果它不工作，我知道如何解决它的问题。
And if it didn't work, I knew how to troubleshoot it.
这是最重要的事情。
That's the important thing.
我知道我们在这里过得很快，但是，同样，这是最重要的事情，它确实...
I know we're going through it quickly here, but, again, this is the most important thing and it does...
它改变了......它使你完全富有成效。
it changes... it makes you totally productive.
现在，到目前为止我已经向你展示了三种方法...
Now, I've shown you three ways so far...
顺便说一下，这...
By the way, and this...
让这些东西在多台机器上工作，我们将更多地谈及远程，但这是你变得如此富有成效的地方。
getting the stuff to work on multiple machines, we're going to talk more about remoting, but that's where you just become so productive.
有多少人在TechEd上找到我，并有这样的故事...有一个...
The number of people who have come up to me at TechEd and had stories like... there's one...
我记得有一个人说，哦，好吧，你知道，他的老板在星期二把大家召集起来，说，哦，我们必须从我们的每一个服务器上得到这些信息，这是头等大事，必须在周末前得到，打电话回家，告诉大家你要加班，不要紧，我们必须把这件事做好。
I remember this one guy who said, oh, well, you know, his boss brings everybody in on like a Tuesday and is like, oh, we got to get this information from every single one of our servers, it's top priority, got to have it by the end of the week, call home, tell the folks you're going to be working late, doesn't matter, we got to get this done.
这就像呃，呃，每个人都像呃，呃，呃。
It's like uh, uh, everybody's like uh, uh, uh.
于是他回到自己的办公室，他想，等一下，我可以用PowerShell做这个。
And so he goes back to his office and he's like, wait a minute, I can do that with PowerShell.
他说，10分钟后，我就掌握了所有的信息。
He says, Ten minutes later, I had all the information.
他说，又花了几分钟时间把它放在Excel电子表格中。
He said, It took a couple more minutes to put it in an Excel spreadsheet.
是的。
Yeah.
所以像15分钟我就完成了。我说，这真是太棒了。
So like 15 minutes I was done. I said, That's awesome.
你做了什么？他说，好吧，我回家了，下午剩下的时间我都休息了。
What did you do? He says, Well, I went home, I took the rest of the afternoon off.
然后他早上回来，给他的老板看了这份很棒的报告，他就说，哦，你是个神。
And then he came back in the morning, showed his boss this awesome report, he's like, Oh, you're a god.
而这也是一种重点，就是我想回家，所以我想把这些东西完成，对吗？而这是你弄清事情的主要方式。
And that's kind of the point, is I want to go home, so I want to get this stuff done, right? And this is a primary way for you to figure out how things work.
因此，到目前为止，我们有三种方法可以做到这一点。
So three ways we've done it so far.
获得服务以停止服务。我们以价值来匹配。
Get service to stop service. We matched by value.
而这就是我们在一开始要尝试的方式。
And that's how we're going to try at the very beginning.
当名词不匹配时，按价值计算可能不会发生。
When the nouns don't match, by value probably isn't going to happen.
并非总是如此，但可能不会发生。
Not always, but probably is not going to happen.
我们确实得到了服务停止的过程，在这个过程中，我们不得不开始按属性名称进行匹配，这意味着传来的属性名称必须与接收命令小程序的参数名称相匹配。
And we did get service stop process where we had to start to match by property name, which means the name of the property coming across has to match the name of the parameter of the receiving commandlet.
顺便说一句，每当你这样做的时候，这时如果是你的朋友。
By the way, whenever you do that, that's where what if is your friend.
哦，是的。这就是 "如果 "绝对是你的朋友的地方。
Oh, yeah. That is where what if is definitely your friend.
第三种方式是，好吧，有一个支持管道输入的参数，你想使用这个参数，但什么...
The third way is, well, there's a parameter that supports pipeline input and you want to use that parameter, but what...
你所发送的财产没有正确的名称。
the property you're sending it doesn't have the right name.
所以你可以用这个语法在飞行中改变它。
So you can change it in flight using this syntax.
这里是第四个，也是最后一个。
Here's the fourth and final.
而且，相信我，那么我们准备在这里休息一下，就在一瞬间。
And, believe me, then we're ready for a break here in just a second.
因此，获得AD电脑。
So get AD computer.
我想让你了解我的业务问题，首先，向你展示有一个小命令...
I want you to understand my business problem, first of all, to show you there's a commandlet...
我们今天不会有很多时间来讨论这个问题，关于WMI的概念，但WMI是最伟大的东西之一。
we're not going to get a lot of time today to spend with this, with the concept of WMI, but WMI is one of the greatest things.
WMI和SIM是世界上最伟大的东西之一。
WMI and SIM are one of the greatest things in the world.
而且我希望稍后杰弗里能够有机会谈一谈。
And I'm hoping that a little bit later on Jeffrey will be able to have a chance to talk about it.
但我只想告诉你，WMI对于抓取各种美妙的信息是很好的。
But I just want to show you WMI is great for grabbing all kinds of wonderful information.
下面是一个WMI只抓取一些BIOS信息的例子。
Here's an example of WMI grabbing just some BIOS information.
我还想指出，这个小命令支持计算机名称，这意味着我可以从多台计算机上得到它。
I also want to point out that this commandlet supports computer name, which means I could get it from multiple computers.
如果我能够正确地拼写它们。
If I could spell them correctly.
所以要明白，这对我来说可能真的很有用。
So understand that this the could be really useful to me.
我可能想做一个完整的硬件清单，但我不会想坐在这里手工输入一堆电脑的名字。
I might want to do a whole hardware inventory, but I'm not going to want to sit here and hand type in a bunch of computer names.
取而代之的是，我想从一个活动目录中管出一堆计算机名称。
Instead I'm going to want to pipe a bunch of computer names from an active directory.
因此，我正在做的是，我将说获得AD计算机，过滤星，管道获得WMI对象。我想要BIOS的类。
So what I'm doing is is I'm going to say get AD computer, filter star, pipe to get WMI object. And I want the class for BIOS.
嗯，事情是这样的。
Well, here's the thing.
你可以在接下来的两天里尝试让这个东西运作起来。
You can spend the next two days trying to get this to work.
这是不可能的。
Ain't gonna happen.
如果你知道如何操作我们在这里向你展示的这个过程，这里就是你要做的，你将在几秒钟内而不是几天内解决这个问题。
If you know how to work this process that we're showing you right here, here's what you would do, and you're going to solve this in seconds rather than days.
首先，你要通过管道到GM，看看对象的类型是什么，因为我们想通过值来检查。
First of all, you're going to pipe to GM to see what the object type is because we want to check for by value.
而我现在要告诉你，按价值计算是行不通的。
And I'm just going to tell you right now by value is not going to work.
我有AD电脑，但按价值来说是不能用的。
I got AD computer, but by value is not going to work.
你知道我怎么知道的吗？因为我们接下来要做的是去看支持管道输入的参数。
You know how I know that? Because the next thing we do is we go look at parameters that support pipeline input.
好吧，我们就这么做吧。获得帮助。
Well, let's do that. Get help.
获取WMI对象的破折号。
Get WMI object dash full.
而且，伙计们，我知道我们可以用展示窗来做这个，但我只是想让你们看到这个的美丽。
And, guys, I know we could do this with the show window, but I just want you to see the beauty of this.
看着它在我进入参数时滚动。
Watch as it scrolls by when I get to the parameters.
节流阀限制，没有。
Throttle limit, no.
回收，没有。
Recurse, no.
查询，没有。属性，没有。
Query, no. Property, no.
被拒绝。
Denied.
名称空间，没有。地点，是的，被拒绝。列表，没有。
Name space, no. Locale, yeah, denied. List, no.
冒充，在星期五晚上很有趣，但是，不。
Impersonation, fun on a Friday night, but, no.
它是过滤器，不，计算机说不。每个参数都说不。
It's filter, no, computer says no. Every parameter says no.
没有管线输入。它不会接受任何管道输入。停止尝试。
No pipeline input. It will not take any pipeline input. Stop trying.
它不会接受任何管道的输入。
It won't take any pipeline input.
所以我经常看到有人说，好吧，那么你不能这样做。它已经坏了。
So I see guys all the time that go, okay, well then you can't do it. It's broke.
他们需要用PowerShell来解决这个问题。
They need to fix that with PowerShell.
嗯，不，你可以做到，只是必须知道如何做。让我告诉你。你知道，我正在给你看...
Well, no, you can do it, just have to know how. Let me show you. You know, I was showing you that...
这个小命令如何获得帮助...
how this commandlet get help...
而我要为它做简短的帮助。
and I'm going to do the short help for it.
这家伙支持冲刺电脑名称。
This guy supports dash computer name.
好吧，在这里我想让你注意到这里。让我们看看破折号电脑的名字。
Well, here I want you to take notice here. Let's look at dash computer name.
看，冲刺电脑名称，他想要的是一串字符串。
See, dash computer name and what he wants is a bunch of strings.
这就是他想要的对象，弦乐。
That's what he wants as an object, strings.
他将采取冲刺的电脑名称，我只是要想办法把它放进去，把那些电脑名称放进去。
He'll take dash computer name, I just have to figure out how to get it in there, get those computer names in there.
因此，我想做的事情是这样的。
So here's what I'd like to do.
获取WMI对象。
Get WMI object.
无论我想上什么课。
Whatever class I want.
我想做的是冲刺计算机名称，并在其中获得计算机名称。我想做的是得到像AD电脑，过滤器，星。
And I would like to do dash computer name and get the computer names in there. I'd like to do get like AD computer, filter, star.
好吧，你不能这样做，因为它搞砸了论证，所以你必须把它们放在括号里。因为记住括号的意思。
Well, you can't do that because it screws up the argument, so you have to put them in parentheses. Because remember what parentheses means.
我不是一个大的数学迷，但那些东西就像操作数的顺序或...
I wasn't a big math fan, but those things are like order of operands or...
你是个聪明人，你知道所有这些东西。那是...
you're a smart guy, you know all that stuff. It's...
它的意思是在我们做其他事情之前先做这个。
it means do this first before we do anything else.
因此，将要发生的事情是，在这些括号里的东西，这个括号，它要先做，这就成为这个破折号电脑名称的参数。但是有一个小问题。
So what's going to happen is what's ever in those parens, this parenthetical, it's going to do that first, and that becomes the argument on this dash computer name. But there's a small problem.
记住破折号计算机名称要一堆字符串对象。
Remember dash computer name wants a bunch of string objects.
我想知道这为我提供了什么。事实上，让我给你看看。
I wonder what this is providing me. As a matter of fact, let me show you.
获得AD电脑。你现在也知道怎么做了。筛选明星。
Get AD computer. And you know how to do this now. Filter star.
这是在生产什么样的物品？把它管到GM。
What kind of object is this producing? Pipe it to GM.
它给我的是AD电脑。
It's giving me AD computer.
这并没有说字符串。
That doesn't say string.
看着吧。另外，它给了我太多的信息。
Watch. Also it's giving me way too much information.
这给了我各种我不想要的东西......
This is giving me all kinds of stuff I don't want...
我只想要名字。我只想选择...
I just want name. I just want to select...
我只想选择名字。所以得到AD电脑。
I just want to select name. So get AD computer.
过滤星。选择属性名称。真棒。我已经得到了这些名字。
Filter star. Select the property name. Awesome. I've got the names.
这就是我想扔进冲锋舟电脑的东西。
This is what I want to throw into dash computer.
但在我们尝试这个之前，请与得到的成员进行检查。
But before we try this, check it with get member.
看一下对象的类型是什么。
Look at what the object type is.
AD电脑。这里没有说字符串。所以它要断了。
AD computer. It doesn't say string here. So it's going to break.
嗯，他们想到了这一点。他们解决了这个问题。
Well, they thought of this. They solved this.
我真正想要的是，我想提取这些名字，并把它们放在那个破折号计算机名称参数中。
What I really want is I want to extract those names and put them in that dash computer name argument.
在[听不清]之间，我想提取...
In between the [Inaudible] I want to extract...
提取这个词并不恰当。
extract isn't the right word.
我想扩展这个属性。现在，你只能扩展一个。
I want to expand this property. Now, you can only expand one.
但在我的屏幕上看看这看起来有什么不同。
But look at the difference on my screen how this looks.
看到你不再有这个了吗？这只是计算机的名称？让我们用管道来获取成员。看吧。字符串。字符串。
See how you don't have this anymore? It's just the names of the computers? Let's pipe it to get member. Looky. String. String.
快乐，快乐。
Happy, happy.
因此，我们所做的是我们......而我将尝试这样做。
So what we do is we... and I'm going to try to do this.
我将尝试右键点击这个。
I'm going to try to right click on this.
这就是我们要做的事情。
And here's what we're going to do.
右击。
Right click.
是的，右击。我想我做对了。因此，获得WMI对象。
Yeah, right click. I think I did that right. So get WMI object.
无论我想在Win32中使用什么类的下划线BIOS冲刺计算机名称。
Whatever class I want in Win32 underscore BIOS dash computer name.
这就是我想放在括号里的内容。
And here's what I want to put inside of the parentheses.
这整个事情。
That whole thing.
现在，你可能会说，哎呀，天哪，那是一个非常大的工作。
Now, you might be saying, gee, whiz, that's an awful lot of work.
但只要你像两三次这样做，就不是什么大工程了。
But as soon as you do this like two or three times, it's not a lot of work.
因为现在你以前无法解决的问题，或者你花了好几天时间敲打你的脑袋的问题，现在正好可以解决。
Because now what you couldn't solve before or you were spending days banging your head on now just works.
而且它只是工作，因为我们无法向这个小命令提供管道，该死，好吧，忘了它，这很好。
And it just works because we couldn't pipeline to this commandlet, darn, okay, forget about it, that's fine.
你想用什么？我想用冲绳的电脑名称。
What do you want to use? I want to use dash computer name.
它想要什么？它想要一个字符串。
What does it want? It wants a string.
所以我想抓住所有的AD计算机。我只想知道属性名称。
So I want to grab all the AD computers. I just want the property name.
我不想要所有其他的属性。我只想要名字。发送给获取成员。
I don't want all the other properties. I just want name. Send it to get member.
这不是一个字符串。哦，我需要扩展这个...
It's not a string. Oh, I need to expand that...
想着把这些......这些值提取出来，我就得到了这个字符串。
think extract that... those values out, and I get the string.
现在它要发挥作用了。这是你最后的手段。
Now it's going to work. This is your last line of resort.
现在，不要把这作为你的第一道防线。
Now, don't use this as your first line of resort.
这不是问题的关键。因为你想要管道的力量。
That's not the point. Because you want the power of the pipeline.
所以不要先做这个。
So don't do this first.
最后做这个。
Do this last.
让我给你看看，我们将让杰弗里谈一谈这个问题，就是在我们休息之前，让我给你看看我发现微软在做什么来帮助我们。
And let me show you, and we're going to let Jeffrey talk about this for a second, is that before we take a break let me show you what I found out Microsoft's kind of doing to help us out.
你知道获取WMI的事情，它不需要任何管道输入？嗯，我碰巧知道，有...
You know how the get WMI thing, it doesn't take any pipeline input? Well, I happen to know that there's...
等等，在你去那里之前...
Wait, before you go there...
哦，是的。是的。
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
向上箭头。
Up arrow.
因为这个工作很完美。这个工作很完美。
Because this works perfectly. This works perfectly.
但这在PowerShell第二版中是可行的。
But this works in PowerShell Version 2.
PowerShell第3版我们把它变得更简单。
PowerShell Version 3 we made it simpler.
哦，让我们把它变得更简单。
Oh, let's make it simpler.
好的，点击删除，删除选择。
Okay. Hit delete, delete the select.
哦，不，不，不，一路从终点到选择。
Oh, no, no, no, all the way from the end of the line to the select.
哦，从终点到选择，一路走来。
Oh, all the way from the end of the line to the select.
是的。摆脱这一切。
Yeah. Get rid of all that.
哦，把这些都去掉吧。
Oh, get rid of all that.
是的。更多。
Yeah. More.
更多？更多的线。好的。现在结束小括号。结束小括号。
More? More line. Okay. Now end paren. End parenthesis.
这就是开始的paren。
That's begin paren.
哦，结束父母。
Oh, end paren.
是的。好的，空间。
Yeah. Okay. Space.
哦，我知道你做了什么。哦。
Oh, I see what you did. Oh.
点名称。
Dot name.
哦，我知道你在做什么了。点名。是的。是的。
Oh, I see what you're doing. Dot name. Yeah. Yeah.
看，这就是交易。那是...
See, that's the deal. That's...
那个点名基本上是速记语法，用来做那个命令行。
that dot name basically is shorthand syntax to do that command line.
这就是你之前用......来展示的。
Which is what you were showing earlier with...
正是....
Exactly....
铸造到XML。
casting to XML.
而且，伙计们，其中一件事是我们要开始向你们展示...
And, guys, one of the things is we're going to start showing you...
当我们接近脚本时，我们将向你展示如何使用变量和使用这个点协同...
as we get close to scripting, we're going to be showing you working with variables and using this dot syn-...
这个点语法，使你越来越适应它，因为现在，只要你对这个点语法有更多的了解，打字就会容易很多。所以这很好。
this dot syntax so you get more and more comfortable with it, because now that was lot a lot easier to type as soon as you know more about that dot syntax. So this is awesome.
看，它仍然起作用。
See, it still worked.
正如我刚刚展示的...
And as I just showed...
哦，让我再给你看看，因为我觉得那东西不在上面。让我给你看看。
oh, let me show you again because I don't think the thing was on there. Let me show you.
哦，发生什么事了？这对你来说很难吗？我可以到那边去。
Oh, what's going on? Is this hard for you? I could go over there.
嗯，不，是... 是... 是...
Well, no, it's... it's...
它的东西已经出了问题，我认为我的...
it's something has gone awry, and I think my...
啊，我们走吧。东西......我们正在等待的电脑。
ah, there we go. Something... the computer we were waiting on.
因此，这个语法，如果你能看到它，是...
So this syntax, if you can see it, is...
它的工作方式完全一样。所以我可以执行它。
it works the exact same way. So I can execute it.
但我不想再做了，因为它在其中一台机器上被撑住了。
But I don't want to do it again because it was holding up on one of the machines.
哦，是这样吗？最后给大家看一件事，然后我们休息一下，就是得到WMI对象不支持任何输入，但有一个...
Oh, was it? One last thing to show you, and then we'll take a break, is get WMI object doesn't support any input, but there's a...
如果你是用WMI工作，有一个全新的方法可以做到这一点。
if you're working with WMI, there's a whole new way of doing this.
如果你要在一个叫做 "获取SIM "的东西上获得帮助，并且你要看一下参数和它们是什么。
And if you were to do get help on something called get SIM instance, and you were to take a look at the parameters and what they...
什么参数接受管道输入，你会看到现在这个是替代这个的。
what parameters accepted pipeline input, you would see that this is now the replacement for this.
因为现在新的支持管道输入，在你希望它支持管道输入的地方。
Because the new one now supports pipeline input in the places where you want it to support pipeline input.
因此，我们的想法是，今后你可能遇到的一些命令，特别是如果它们是四、五年前的，确实需要支持线输入，可能会开始支持它。
So the idea is that going forward some of the commands that you may run across, especially if they're four or five years old that did need support line input, may start to support it.
但是，如果没有，你确实有这最后的手段。
But if it doesn't, you do have this last line of resort.
现在，作为最后的说明，请确保...
Now, as a final note, make sure...
这是非常重要的，那么，你得到...
this is so very important, well, you get...
我打算再给他们看一件东西。
I was going to show them one more thing.
哦，去吧。再给他们看一样东西。
Oh, go ahead. Show them one more thing.
好的，我将接管你的机器。
Okay. I'm going to take over your machine.
好吧，都是你的了，伙计。
Okay. It's all yours, man.
好的。这并不奏效。是的，没错。当然了。好吧。
Okay. This did not work. Yeah, right. Of course. Okay.
在这里，我们走了。
Here we go.
好吧，我接管他的机器。
Okay. I'm taking over his machine.
他要接管我的机器。
He's going to take over my machine.
在他接手的时候，请买唐-琼斯的书，《在一个月的午餐中学习Windows PowerShell》，第九章。
While he's taking it over, get Don Jones' book, Learn Windows PowerShell in a Month of Lunches, chapter 9.
你必须知道这一点。这是最重要的事情。
You've got to know that. That's the most important thing.
这就是我们刚才在这里所做的。
That's what we just did in here.
好吧，好吧，好吧，好吧。
Okay.
所以现在我要给你看一些疯狂的怪异的东西，怪异的，怪异的，怪异的，强大的。
So now I'm going to show you something crazy freaky, freaky, freaky, freaky powerful.
哦，让我们变得怪异吧。
Oh, let's get freaky.
是的，我们将变得怪异。
Yeah, we're going to get freaky.
怪异，怪异，怪异。
Freaky, freaky, freaky.
好的，对不起。
Okay, sorry.
安定下来。
Settle down.
[好的，所以这是很高级的东西。
[Laugher] Okay. So this is pretty advanced stuff.
但为什么不以真正有力量的东西来结束呢。
But why not end on something really powerful.
好吗？这个东西叫做...
Okay? And this is something called...
我们怎么称呼这些？我们称这些为脚本参数，我想这是它们的术语。
what do we call these? We call these script parameters, I think is the term for them.
所以现在我们要做的是，记住，原来的问题是得到AD计算机减去过滤器的星形管道，以获得WMI对象Win32 BIOS，而且是这个计算机名称，我们无法得到一个值。
So now what we're going to do is, remember, the original problem was get AD computer minus filter star pipe to get WMI object Win32 BIOS, and it was this computer name that we couldn't get a value for.
对。
Right.
该死的。好吧，那么事情是这样的。
Darn. Okay. So here's the deal.
脚本块。每当你看到...
Script block. Whenever you see the...
你怎么称呼它们？壁虎？Squigglies。
what do you call them? The squigglies? Squigglies.
是的，我喜欢自己做臀部，但为了方块字。
Yeah, I like to do my hips myself, but for the squigglies.
每当你看到这些方块，那就叫作脚本块。
Whenever you see the squigglies, that's called a script block.
这代表代码。
That represents code.
如果你给一个属性一个脚本块，给一个不接受脚本块的参数，那么它就是，哦，你一定是在要求一个脚本参数。
If you give a script block to a property, to a parameter which doesn't take a script block, then what it is is, oh, you must be asking for a script parameter.
它所做的是获取当前对象的值，将其分配给美元符号下栏，并运行脚本，获取该值并将其放入其中。
And what it does is it takes the value of the current object, assigns it to dollar sign underbar and runs the script and takes the value and puts it in there.
哦，这可能是完全令人敬畏的。
Oh, this could be totally awesome.
所以你说的是，你说美元符号下栏点...
And so what you say is you say dollar sign underbar dot...
是名字吗？是名字。
was it name? It was name.
名字。好的，顺便说一下，你可以在这里做任何你想做的事情。
Name. Okay. By the way, you can do anything you want here.
你可以对上说，你知道，任何事情。
You could say to upper, you know, anything.
但在这里，我们只是做这个。
But here we just do this.
所以，同样，将要发生的是你要运行这个，你要把当前对象，你要把它分配给这个，然后你要运行这个代码。
So, again, what's going to happen is you're going to run this, you're going to take the current object, you're going to assign it to this, and then you're going to run this code.
所以每个对象你都要得到名字的值，然后你要用这个值来运行这个。
And so each object you're going to get the value of the name, and then you're going to run this with the value.
那是疯狂的力量还是什么？你知道，你意识到你已经让这一切变得如此简单，以至于每个人都会喜欢你，而不是喜欢我了。
Is that crazy powerful or what? You know, you realize that you've made that so much easier that everybody's going to like you better than they like me now.
是的，我知道。
Yeah, I know.
因为我给他们下药，通过那么长的...
Because I drug them through that long...
这就是计划。
That's the plan.
好吧，这很有效，因为我带着他们经历了那件漫长的事情，然后你就把它变得非常简短和甜蜜。
Okay, well, it worked because I took them through that long thing and then you just made it really short and sweet.
是的。
Yeah.
恭喜你。非常好的工作。
Congratulations. Very nice job.
你去那里。所以，请尽情享受吧。
There you go. So have fun with that.
所以，伙计们，我们要继续下去，休息10分钟。
So, folks, we're going to go ahead and take a ten-minute break.
当我们回来的时候，我们进入了...
When we come back, we get into...
给他拿点咖啡。
Get him some coffee.
是的，是的，给我一些咖啡，因为我需要更多。
Yeah, yeah, get me some coffee because I need more.
而我们将进入一些将改变你管理方式的东西。
And we're going to go into something that is going to change the way you manage.
现在你将利用你今天开始学习的工具，我们将进入世界上最强大的东西之一，即远程。
Now you're going to take the tools that you started to learn today and we're going to get into one of the most powerful things in the world, remoting.
在我们进入这个话题之前，我们想和Jeffrey谈谈遥控的问题。这完全是了不起的东西。
And we want to talk to Jeffrey about remoting before we get into it. This is totally awesome stuff.
那么，十分钟后见吧。
So see you guys in ten minutes.